The Charles Shackford Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Charles Shackford Papers
1934-1984
MSS 38
Yale University Music Library
10.4
(22 boxes)
Music, correspondence and other writings, photographs, and additional materials by and about the American composer, conductor, and teacher Charles Shackford (1918-1979)
Shackford, Charles
Conditions Governing Access
The Papers are open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Charles Shackford Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Jane Wilson Shackford in 1980.
Arrangement
In 12 series as follows: I. Music. II. Writings by Charles Shackford. III. Correspondence. IV. Programs. V. Photographs. VI. Student materials. VII. Teaching materials. VIII. Biographical materials. IX. Memorabilia. X. Clippings and articles. XI. Miscellaneous items. XII. Sound recordings.
Scope and Contents
The Charles Shackford Papers contain the manuscript sketches and scores of Shackford's musical compositions, including orchestral music, choral and chamber works, songs, and arrangements of music by other composers. The correspondence includes letters to and from Shackford and composers, performers, publishers, and musical organizations. Shackford's life and work are further documented by: programs; photographs and biographical materials; teaching materials; clippings and articles; and miscellaneous items.
Biographical / Historical
Charles Reeve Shackford was born in New York City on April 18, 1918. After high school in California and New York, he entered Yale College in 1937 and received the B.A. in 1941. In 1942 he was awarded a bachelor of music degree, and in 1944, a master's, both from the Yale School of Music. His teachers at Yale included Paul Hindemith, David Stanley Smith, Frank Bozyan, and Ralph Kirkpatrick. During this time he also attended the Juilliard Summer School, receiving a certificate in music theory in 1940.
From 1944 to 1946 Shackford taught at Bennett Junior College in Millbrook, New York. Then, in the fall of 1946, he entered Harvard Graduate School, where he held fellowships studying composition and teaching counterpoint from 1947 to 1950. In 1949 he began work on his doctoral dissertation, Intonation in Ensemble String Performance. He was awarded the Ph.D. in 1954 and stayed on until 1956 as a research fellow in acoustics. His teachers at Harvard included Walter Piston and Archibald T. Davison. Among the compositions from this time are the String Trio (1947), the Fantasy for Violoncello and Piano (1951), and the Trio for Winds (1952).
From 1952 to 1962 he was active in numerous capacities, working as an organist and choral conductor, directing the choir and lecturing in music history at Wellesley College from 1952 to 1953, holding posts at churches in the Boston area, leading the Belmont Community Chorus (from 1955 to 1959--he was their first director), directing music at the School of Nursing, Newton-Wellesley Hospital (1956-1962), and playing recitals. He was active in scientific endeavors as well, holding a Ford Foundation fellowship researching acoustics and musical perception, and conducting research in meteorology. Some compositions from this period are the Te Deum in C (1956), An Ode to Learning (1959), and psalm settings.
From 1962 to 1965 Shackford was an associate professor of music and chairman of the music department at Wilson College in Chambersburg, Pennsylvania. There he conducted the choir, taught, and continued his acoustical research. Only the Nunc Dimittis (1964) is listed as from this time.
In 1964 he was appointed a visiting professor at Connecticut College, and in 1966 he was made a full professor, holding the chairmanship of his department from 1969 to 1972. These years at Connecticut College, from 1965 to his death in 1979, saw his most intense and fruitful work in composition. Much of this was chamber music, including the Quintet in E-flat (1973) and the two string quartets (1977 and 1979). There are also choral works, such as his Psalm 139 for solo baritone, chorus, and orchestra. But, perhaps most importantly, these are the years of his first efforts in large-scale composition, namely, the Fantasy on Vysehrad for two pianos and orchestra (1969), the Overture Concertante for band (1974), and the Concerto for Brass and Symphonic Ensemble (1976). Shackford was under commission to write a work for the Minnesota Orchestra when his life was suddenly cut short in an automobile accident in New London, Connecticut on April 21, 1979.
Composers -- Correspondence; Music -- United States -- 20th Century; Piano music; Songs; String quartets -- Scores; Althouse, Paul, 1889-1954; Anderson, Ruth; Austin, William W., 1920-2000; Bingham, Susan Hulsman, 1944-; Boatwright, Howard, 1918-1999; Boyden, David D. (David Dodge), 1910-1986; Bozyan, H. Frank (Hagop Frank), 1899-1965; Brown, Howard Mayer, 1930-; Coffin, William Sloane, Jr., 1924-2006; Cohen, Isidore, 1922-2005; Cohn, Arthur, 1910-1998; Davison, Archibald T. (Archibald Thompson), 1883-1961; Duckles, Vincent H. (Vincent Harris), 1913-1985; Dunn, Thomas; Fiedler, Arthur, 1894-1979; Forte, Allen, 1926-2014; French, Richard F. (Richard Frederic), 1915-2001; Fuller, Albert, 1926-2007; Grasso, Ella, 1919-1981; Grout, Donald Jay, 1902-1987; Hancock, Gerre, 1934-2012; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963; Husa, Karel, 1921-2016; Kirkpatrick, John, 1905-1991; Lurtsema, Robert J.; Marriner, Neville, 1924-2016; McKinley, Carl, 1895-1966; Miller, Carl S., 1917-2001; Newcomb, Anthony, 1943-; Noss, Luther, 1907-1995; Palisca, Claude V., 1921-2001; Piston, Walter, 1894-1976; Sargeant, Winthrop, 1903-1986; Schwartz, Elliott, 1936-2016; Self, William, 1921-2010; Serkin, Rudolf, 1903-1991; Shackford, Charles; Simonds, Bruce; Skrowaczewski, Stanisław, 1923-2017; Smith, Carleton Sprague, 1905-1994; Waite, William G.; Weicker, Lowell P., Jr. (Lowell Palmer), 1931-; Weinrich, Carl, 1904-; Wilson, Keith L. (Keith Leroy), 1916-2013; Winograd, Arthur, 1920-2010; Zaslaw, Neal, 1939-
- Music, 19---1979; Series I; 6.3' (12 boxes)
  General
  This series contains holograph, manuscript, photocopied, and published music by Shackford and others. It is divided into four subseries: A. By Charles Shackford; B. By Others, Arranged by Charles Shackford; C. By Others; and D. By Charles Shackford, Oversize Materials. Within subseries A. and D., works are arranged chronologically by year, and alphabetically by title within a given year. If items lack dates, these are often taken from the list of compositions that accompanies his resume, or from the family's inventory, both to be found in Series VIII. Biographical Material. Those items in subseries A. which could not be dated are assigned the date 19--, and are placed at the beginning of the subseries, as most of them are almost certainly products of his high school and Yale years. Within subseries B. and C., works are arranged alphabetically by composer. The order of descriptions of items pertaining to a given work conforms to the order that represents the development of that work. A typical sequence would be: sketches, fair score, master sheets of score, master sheets of parts, photocopy of the master score, and photocopy of the master parts. Arrangements of a work are described after the original version. An alphabetical index by genre of the music by Shackford has been included at the end of the register. Uniform titles are used to bring together all manifestations of a work with various titles, and are used once for two or more entries. Cross-references refer from other titles of a work, from titles of its parts, or from titles of other works with which an item is to be found ("with" references), to the uniform title. Identification of sketches was often difficult, and unidentified sketches are to be found throughout the music.
  - Music by Charles Shackford, I.A
    See also: I.D. Music by Charles Shackford, Oversize Materials.
    - Chorale for four instruments
      See: Selections.
    - Chorale tune from--Koechlin
    - [Fugues (Sketches)] Fugue[s]. -- [19--]., [20] p. of music; 32-36 cm. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      "Fugue for three parts"--Container.
      Sketches for fugues and unidentified works.
      For three unspecified instruments.
    - [Fugues, string trio, A minor] Fugue in A minor. -- [19--]., 3 parts; 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Holograph signed, in ink with black, red, and blue pencil holograph and manuscript markings.
    - [Invention, string trio] Invention for string trio. -- [19--]., 1 score (p. [4], 2, 3); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Holograph in ink.
      With: Melody, string quartet.
    - [Melody, string quartet] Melody. -- [19--]., 1 score (p. 1, [41); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Holograph signed, in ink.
      With: Invention, string trio.
    - [Mercury] Mercury., [3] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Holograph signed, in ink with black pencil holograph and red pencil manuscript markings.
      For piano.
      Used later as 5th movement of Suites, piano (1970).
    - Mixolydian mode (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - [Music, piano, orchestra (Sketches)] Music for piano and orchestra. -- [19--]., 1 short score ([32] p.); 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Holograph signed, in ink with black and red pencil manuscript markings.
      Incomplete.
      With: Piano music. Selections (Sketches).
    - O Lord, in the morning shalt thou hear my voice (Box 1, Folder 5)
      See: Psalm 5, mixed solo voices.
    - Original chorale tunes set freely (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - [Piano music. Selections (Sketches)], [8] sheets of music; 24-32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      With: Music, piano, orchestra (Sketches).
    - Piano pieces (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - [Piece, string trio] Piece for three strings. -- [19--]. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Holograph signed, in ink with pencil holograph and manuscript markings.
    - [Prelude, piano] Prelude. -- [19--]., 3 leaves of music; 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Holograph signed, in ink with red pencil manuscript markings and comments.
      "Theory 21 Final Assignment"--T.p.
    - [Psalm 5, mixed solo voices] Psalm 5: verse 3: set for mixed trio., 1 vocal score ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      For solo voices (SAB).
      1 vocal score ([2] p.); 32 cm.
      Holograph signed, in pencil.
      Holograph in pencil.
    - [Selections (Sketches)], [46] p., [8] sheets, [14] p., [28] sheets of music; 10-35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Holograph in pencil and ink with red and blue pencil manuscript markings.
      "Manuscript Fragments I"--Container.
    - [Selections (Sketches)], [36] sheets, [10] p., [17] sheets of music; 18-37 cm. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Holograph in ink and pencil with some red pencil manuscript markings.
      "Manuscript Fragments II"--Container.
      Includes manuscript copies of music by others.
    - [Selections (Sketches)], [23] leaves of music; 17-34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Miscellaneous sketches, including a string quartet, a scherzo for piano, and a choral work.
    - [Selections], [13] p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Holograph signed, in ink with red and black pencil markings.
      Contents: Chorale tune from-Koechlin - Mixolydian mode -- Original chorale tunes set freely -- Chorale for four instruments [oboe, viola, bassoon, violoncello] -- Piano pieces: 1. Whimsey; 2. Theme; 3. Little study 4. Ground and air; 5. Prelude.
      "Harmony/--strict and free. Composition"--T.p.
      No. 1-3 and 5 of Piano pieces used later in Suites, piano (1970).
      Chiefly keyboard music.
    - [Sonata allegro, string trio] Sonata allegro for string trio. -- [19--]., 1 score ([8] p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      "Sonata movement"--Caption.
    - [Suites, flute, strings (Sketches)] Suite for flute and strings. -- [19--]., [6] sheets of music; 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Holograph in pencil with red pencil manuscript markings.
      Title from container.
      For flute, violin, viola, and violoncello.
      Includes unidentified sketches.
    - Six variations on a Swiss tune from Heidi -- 1937 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      See: Variations on a Swiss tune.
    - [Sonata movement, piano] Sonata movement for piano. -- 1937., 7 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Holograph signed in ink, with pencil markings.
      Dated: "Far Hills, N.J. Sept. 1937.".
    - [Variations on a Swiss tune] Six variations on a Swiss tune from "Heidi". -- 1937., [3] p. of music; 32. cm. (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Holograph signed, in ink with pencil markings.
      Dated: "Far Hills N.J., December 1937".
    - Five variations on a theme from "Snow White". -- 1938. (Box 1, Folder 16)
      See: Variations on a theme from Snow White.
    - [Variations on a theme from Snow White] Five variations on a theme from "Snow White". -- 1938., 5 [i.e. 4] p. of music; 42 cm. (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Dated: "Far Hills N.J., March 31, 1938".
    - [At the window], 1 score ([2] leaves); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Holograph signed, in ink with typescript text and red and black pencil manuscript markings.
      For voice amd violin.
      Words by James Reeve[s].
      1 part; 35 cm.
      Holograph signed, in ink with pencil manuscript markings.
      Violin part.
      1 score ([2] sheets); 36 cm.
      Holograph (photocopy) signed.
      1 part; 36 cm.
    - Bad dreams. I (Box 1, Folder 18)
      See: Songs, piano acc. Selections.
    - A bargain (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Echo (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - [Fantasies, piano, C major] Fantasie in C major. -- 1939., 5 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Dated: "New Haven, March 1939".
      Includes unidentified pencil sketches on verse, p. 5.
    - [Follow thy fair sun, unhappy shadow] Follow thy fair sun, unhappy shadow. -- [1939]., 1 score ([5] p.); 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Holograph signed, in ink with typescript text and red and black pencil markings.
      For voice, violin, and viola.
      Words by Campion.
      Title from violin part.
      2 parts; 35 cm.
      Violin and viola parts.
      1 score ([4] sheets); 47 cm.
      2 parts; 47 cm.
    - [I saw the moon rise], 4 p. of music; 27 cm. (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Holograph in pencil and ink with red pencil markings.
      For voice and piano.
      Composed ca. 1939
    - [Rondo scherzando], Rondo scherzando. -- 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Identical to 2nd movement, Sonatas, piano, A.
      Dated: "New Haven, June 1939".
    - [Sonatas, piano, A] Sonata in A for piano. -- [ca. 1939?]., [17] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Holograph signed, in ink and pencil.
      Contains 1st and 2nd movements, 4th movement (incomplete), and 4th movement sketches.
      2nd movement identical to Rondo scherzando.
      Note by Roger Blanc laid in.
    - [Songs, piano acc. Selections] Songs. -- [1939]., 1 score (24 p.); 22 cm. (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Contents: A bargain / [words by] Sir Philip Sidney -- Wantings is--what? / [words by] Robert Browning -- Bad dreams I / [words by] Browning -- Echo / [words by] Thomas Moore -- When thou art nigh / [words by] Thomas Moore.
      Words typed separately as text before each song.
    - [Trios, piano, horn, violin, F major] Allegro movement for horn, violin and piano in F major. -- 1939., 1 score ([29] p.); 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 25)
      "Horn trio in F"--Cover.
      Dated: "Far Hills N.J. September 1939"--T.p.; "19/9/39"--At end.
      2 parts; 32 cm.
      Holograph in ink and pencil.
      Horn and violin parts.
    - Wanting is--what? (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - When thou art nigh (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - [Aus der Spaziergang (Sketches)] Aus der "Spaziergang" / von F. Schiller. -- [194-]., [21] sheets of music 31-32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Holograph in pencil with red and blue pencil manuscript markings.
      For baritone and piano.
      Includes unidentified sketches and extensive manuscript markings.
    - [Canon, flute, viola, continuo] Canon in the 7th. -- [194-]., 1 score ([2] p.) 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Continuo line incomplete.
    - [German folksongs (Sketches)], [7] sheets of music; 19-34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Holograph in pencil and ink with red pencil and ink manuscript markings.
      Includes tunes and texts of other folksongs, and unidentified sketches.
    - [German folksongs] German folksongs in two voice settings. -- (194-], 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 28)
      For voice with unspecified instrumental accompaniment (?).
    - [Fugues, voices (4)] Fugue in four voices. -- [194-]., 1 score ([4] p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 29)
      For unspecified instruments.
    - Sir Patric Spens (Box 1, Folder 29)
      See: Variations, men's voices.
    - [Selections (Sketches)], [5, 12, 7, 7, 20] sheets of music; 22-34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Holograph in pencil with extensive red pencil manuscript markings.
      "Hindemith I"--Container.
    - [Sonatinas, piano, trumpet (Sketches)], 5 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 31)
      "Trumpet Sonatina by Charles Shackford with correction--red pencil by Paul Hindemith"--Container.
    - [Variations, men's voices (Sketches)], [4] sheets of music; 31 cm. (Box 2, Folder 32)
      Sheet [2] includes unidentified sketches.
    - [Variations, men's voices] Theme and variations: for a capella male chorus a setting of the Scottish ballade Sir Patric Spens. -- [194-]., 1 score (10 p.); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 32)
      For men's chorus (TTBB).
    - [Serenades, piano, chamber orchestra] Serenade for piano and chamber group. -- [1942]., 1 score (29 p. ); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 33)
      Holograph, signed in pencil.
    - [Trios, oboe, violin, viola], 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - [Duets, violin, viola] -- 1943, 1 score ([1] leaf); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 36)
      With: Sonatinas, oboe, harp (Sketches).
    - [Sonatinas, oboe, harp (Sketches)], 1 score ([19] p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - [Sonatinas, oboe, harp (Sketches)], [13] sheets of music; 27-34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 36)
      Contains extensive corrections.
      With: Duet, violin, viola.
    - [Sonatinas, oboe, harp], 1 score ([11] p.); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 37)
      Holograph in ink with black and red pencil manuscript markings.
      See also: D. By Charles Shackford, Oversize materials.
    - [Movement, trumpet, piano], 1 score (5 p.); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 38)
      Holograph signed, in pencil with red pencil manuscript markings.
      Dated: 1944.
    - [Movement, trumpet, piano] Movement for trumpet. -- 1944., 1 part; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 38)
      Trumpet part.
      "Mr. Hindemith's class at Yale"--T.p.
    - [Slow movement, clarinet, piano], 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - [Slow movement, clarinet, piano] Slow movement, clarinet. -- [1944]., 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 39)
      Holograph signed, in ink with red pencil manuscript markings.
      "Clarinet Piece"--Caption.
    - [Small symphony (Sketches)], [19] sheets, 12 p. of music; 20-35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 40)
      "Master's Thesis ? (Yale)"--Container.
      Includes extensive corrections.
    - [Small symphony] Small symphony in F. -- [ca. 1944?]., 1 score (23, 15, 33 p.); 55 cm. (Box 2, Folder 41)
      Holograph signed, in ink (1st movement) and pencil (2nd and 3rd movements) with red pencil manuscript markings (2nd and 3rd movements).
      "Revised 1/46"--End of 1st movement.
      2nd and 3rd movements incomplete.
    - [Small symphony. Jaunty] Small symphony in F: I. -- [ca. 1944?]., 1 score (28 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 41)
      Holograph in pencil with red pencil markings.
      1st movement.
    - [Sonatinas, piano] Movement for piano sonatina. -- 1943-1944., [3] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 42)
      Holograph signed, in ink
      "Mr. Hindemith's Class at Yale 1943-1944"--T.p.
    - [Counterpoint with Walter Piston], [4], [16], [6] sheets; 28-32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 43)
      "Counterpoint with Walter Piston. 1946-1947"--Container.
      Contains exercises, class notes, etc.
    - [Duets, clarinets], 1 score (4 sheets); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 44)
      Holograph signed, in pencil with blue pencil markings.
      Dated: 1947.
    - [Duets, clarinets, arr.] Duo for alto & tenor saxophones. -- 1947, c1976., 1 score ([2] sheets); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 44)
      Holograph transparency signed, in ink.
    - [Duets, clarinets, arr.] Duo for alto & tenor saxophones. -- 1947, c1976., 1 score ([2] p.]; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Duo for alto & tenor saxophones (Box 2, Folder 44)
      See: Duets, clarinets, arr.
    - String trio (Box 2, Folder 44)
      See: Trios, strings, A.
    - [Trios, strings, A], 1 score ([9], 6, 8, [i.e. 10] sheets); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - [Trios, strings, A] Trio in A. -- [c1947]., 3 parts; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 46)
      Holograph signed, in ink with black and blue pencil manuscript markings.
    - [Trios, strings, A] String trio. -- c1947., 1 score (22 sheets); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 47)
      Holograph transparency signed, in ink with blue ink and green pencil markings.
      "Here and elsewhere there exist differences in notation between score and parts. Parts were altered for players' convenience."--Sheet 1.
    - [Trios, strings, A] String trio 1. -- 1947, [c1947]., 3 parts; 25-36 cm. (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Holograph transparency, signed in ink.
    - [Trios, strings, A] String trio. -- [c1947]., 1 score (12, 10 leaves); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 49)
      Holograph (photocopy) signed, with blue pencil markings.
    - [Trios, strings, A] String trio. -- [c1947]., 1 score (22 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - [Trios, strings, A] String trio. -- c1947., 1 score (22 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 51)
      Copyright added in ink, p. 1.
      Holograph title, cover.
    - [Trios, strings, A] String trio 1. -- 1947, [c1947]., 3 parts; 32-35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - [Duets, horn, violoncello, F] Duo-sonate [sic] in F for horn & cello. -- [1949]., 1 score (6 p.); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - [Duets, horn, violoncello, F] Duo sonata, French horn & cello. -- [1949]. (Box 2, Folder 53)
      Horn part.
    - [Duets, horn, violoncello, F] Duo-sonate [sic], French horn and cello. -- [1949]., 1 part; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 53)
      Violoncello part.
    - Duo sonata, French horn, cello (Box 2, Folder 53)
      See: Duets, horn, violoncello.
    - [Fantasies, violoncello, piano, F (Sketches)], [9] p. of music. (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - [Fantasies, violoncello, piano, F] Fantasy-sonata in F for cello and piano. -- 1951, [c1951]., 1 score (29 p.); 34 cm. (Box 3, Folder 55)
      Dated: "Malden Mass. July 1951."
    - [Fantasies, violoncello, piano, F] Fantasy-sonata in F for cello and piano. -- 1951, [c1951]., 1 score ([17] sheets); 25-35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 56)
      Holograph transparency in ink.
    - [Fantasies, violoncello, piano, F] Fantasy-sonata in F for cello and piano. -- 1951, [c1951]., 1 part; 32-34 cm. (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - [Fantasies, violoncello, piano, F] Fantasy-sonata in F for cello and piano. -- 1951, [c1951]., 1 score (30 p.); 34 cm. (Box 3, Folder 58)
      Holograph (photocopy) signed, with pencil and ink manuscript and holograph markings.
      Earlier version of work.
    - [Fantasies, violoncello, piano, F] Fantasy-sonata in F for cello and piano. -- c1951., 1 score (30 p.); 34-36 cm. (Box 3, Folder 59)
      Holograph transparency signed, in ink and pencil.
      Dedication: "To Teddy Rex."
      Dated: "Malden Mass. July 1951".
      Revised version with some old master sheets.
    - [Fantasies, violoncello, piano, F] Fantasy in F. -- c1951, 1 part; 23-32 cm. (Box 3, Folder 60)
      Violoncello part with revisions.
    - [Fantasies, violoncello, piano, F] Fantasy in F for violoncello and piano. -- c1951., 1 score (30 p.), bound; 36 cm. (Box 3, Folder 61)